<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on ODEF</title>
    <link>https://www.odef.wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on ODEF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 21:29:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.odef.wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Purpose ODEF enables organization to create and apply principles and best practices for detection engineering. Utilizing it leads to service and process improvements and maturity.
The Framework focuses on using business goals and outcomes to drive and guide cybersecurity activities to deliver detections, improve visibility, minimize vendor dependencies and ultimately improve the organization security posture. The Framework provides the principles that guide efficient and effective detection engineering practices and also provides three maturity levels to measure the organization performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Maturity is a self-evaluation process conducted by the team. ODEF provides guidance and structure and assures that all the relevant areas are covered. The goal of the review process is to give a baseline that helps achieving a common understanding about the organization security posture.
Dimentions Threat Detection Content Assurance Knowledge sharing flowchart RL Assurance(Assurance) &lt;---&gt;Threat[Threat Detection Content] Knowledge[Knowledge sharing] &lt;---&gt; Assurance(Assurance) Knowledge[Knowledge sharing] &lt;---&gt; Threat(Threat Detection Content) Maturity levels Level 1 - Partial Threat Detection Content Organizational threat identification practices rely solely on external vendors to provide security content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operational Maturity</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/operational-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/operational-maturity/</guid>
      <description>Maturity Review Process (MRP) The process of evaluating the maturity:
Collect - Collect information about your processes,people and tools. Identify changes to any. The goal is to gain a holistic understanding of the organization&#39;s security teams, tools and processes. Based on that information various posture improvements can be identified. Analize - Based on the data that you have collected and find the corresponding maturity level. Finding where in the maturity level the organization is important for understanding the impact and importance of each identified security improvement initiative and thus prioritize accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Template</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/knowledge/doc-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/knowledge/doc-template/</guid>
      <description>Template should be used to standardize the detection content and create a knowledge base
Detection Summary Status (developing/active/decommissioned) Goal (Why) The goal of the detection TTP (What) Mitre attack link Strategy (How) Query or short explanation about it Automation (When) Schedule and automation details Sources (Where) Data sources used for the detection Severity high/medium/low Priority high/medium/low Research Goal The goal section provides the intended purpose of the alert. It is a simple, plaintext description of the type of behavior you&amp;rsquo;re attempting to detect and why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/framework-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/framework-core/</guid>
      <description>Framework Core The Framework Core provides a set of activities to achieve specific cybersecurity outcomes and references examples of how to achieve those outcomes.
Functions, Goals, Guidelines There are set of functions, goals and guidelines for each phase from the detection lifecycle. Functions, goals, guidelines help the detection engineer to have north star focus and deliver a detection with exceptional quality.
Functions Similarly to python functions those are single goal activities that return or drive particular outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunrise/</guid>
      <description>Phase 1️⃣ Sunrise 🌅 Sunrise is the first phase of the detection lifecycle. It marks the inception, development and deployment of the detection. During that phase there are 6 core functions that should be addressed:
Research Prepare (Logging) Build (Detection Content) Validate Automate Share (Knowledge) High level goals for the Sunrise phase Build high fidelity detection Ensure detection validation Create documentation Integrate and automate in the environment Socialize the detection with the security organization Functions Goal Description Guidelines Research Opportunity Identification It can be triggered from analyzing threat intelligence reports, or OSINT, or internal knowledge for a particular security gap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midday</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/midday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/midday/</guid>
      <description>Phase 2️⃣ Midday ☀️ The “Midday” phase is normally the longest phase from the detection lifecycle, during which the detection has been engineered and commissioned to production. The phase monitors the detection during its operation and aims to improve it if needed. High level goals for the Midday phase: Operate and monitor the detection for FP or TP Improve the detection logic in case of influx of FP Perform systematic reviews to ensure relevancy Functions Goal Description Guidelines Monitor&lt;/&gt; Run as per defined schedule Detection is configured to run on pre-defined schedule or real time if applicable Detections will run based on the schedule set during the sunrise phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunset/</guid>
      <description>Phase 3️⃣ Sunset 🌆 During the “Sunset” phase the detection is taken out of commission. The phase wants to ensure that resources are not spent for outdated detections that are no longer applicable and at the same time leave sufficient trace of the existence of the detection. High level goals for the Sunset phase:
Decommission the detection and leave it in a state that it can be resumed anytime Preserve knowledge Functions Goal Description Guidelines Decommission Decommission the detection The goal is to decommission the detection by following process that provides visibility In order to decommission a detection simply change the status field to &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/dac/odef-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/dac/odef-templates/</guid>
      <description>Template Purpose ODEF provides two templates for documenting detections — yaml and markdown. Each for different purpose:
Yaml is used due to its data serialization and wide programming language compatibility. It is used for automation and integrations with other systems. It stores components like the queries, baseline, schedule and others. It is a stepping stone for Detection-as-Code capability.
Markdown is used for detection documentation due to its readability and simplicity. Especially helpful for knowledge sharing when used in conjunction with platforms like GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The yaml file</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/dac/yml-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/dac/yml-file/</guid>
      <description>Yaml file purpose status: &amp;#34;{{ status }}&amp;#34; created_date: &amp;#34;{{ created_date }}&amp;#34; last_updated_date: name: &amp;#34;{{ detection_name }}&amp;#34; query: &amp;#34;{{ query }}&amp;#34; author: &amp;#34;{{ detection_author }}&amp;#34; schedule: &amp;#34;{{ schedule }}&amp;#34; baseline: &amp;#34;{{ baseline }}&amp;#34; visualization: &amp;#34;{{ visualization }}&amp;#34; event_limit: 0 data_source: &amp;#34;{{ data_source }}&amp;#34; data_location: &amp;#34;{{ data_source }}&amp;#34; tactic: &amp;#34;{{ tactic }}&amp;#34; mitre_id: &amp;#34;{{ mitre_id }}&amp;#34; mitre_url: &amp;#34;{{ mitre_url }}&amp;#34; incident: severity: &amp;#34;numeric, 0-unknown, 0.5 - informational, 1-low,2-medium,3-high,4-critical&amp;#34; type: &amp;#39;Security Incident&amp;#39; name: &amp;#39;string, name of the incident&amp;#39; description: &amp;#39;inc descr: This detection is monitoring for changes in any of X&amp;#39; sla: &amp;#39;integer - number of minutes added to incident create time(incident sla).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
