<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DEMM on ODEF</title>
    <link>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DEMM on ODEF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.odef.wiki/demm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Maturity is a self-evaluation process conducted by the team. ODEF provides guidance and structure and assures that all the relevant areas are covered. The goal of the review process is to give a baseline that helps achieving a common understanding about the organization security posture.
Dimentions Threat Detection Content Assurance Knowledge sharing flowchart RL Assurance(Assurance) &lt;---&gt;Threat[Threat Detection Content] Knowledge[Knowledge sharing] &lt;---&gt; Assurance(Assurance) Knowledge[Knowledge sharing] &lt;---&gt; Threat(Threat Detection Content) Maturity levels Level 1 - Partial Threat Detection Content Organizational threat identification practices rely solely on external vendors to provide security content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operational Maturity</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/operational-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/demm/operational-maturity/</guid>
      <description>Maturity Review Process (MRP) The process of evaluating the maturity:
Collect - Collect information about your processes,people and tools. Identify changes to any. The goal is to gain a holistic understanding of the organization&#39;s security teams, tools and processes. Based on that information various posture improvements can be identified. Analize - Based on the data that you have collected and find the corresponding maturity level. Finding where in the maturity level the organization is important for understanding the impact and importance of each identified security improvement initiative and thus prioritize accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
