<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phases on ODEF</title>
    <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phases on ODEF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 21:29:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunrise/</guid>
      <description>Phase 1️⃣ Sunrise 🌅 Sunrise is the first phase of the detection lifecycle. It marks the inception, development and deployment of the detection. During that phase there are 6 core functions that should be addressed:
Research Prepare (Logging) Build (Detection Content) Validate Automate Share (Knowledge) High level goals for the Sunrise phase Build high fidelity detection Ensure detection validation Create documentation Integrate and automate in the environment Socialize the detection with the security organization Functions Goal Description Guidelines Research Opportunity Identification It can be triggered from analyzing threat intelligence reports, or OSINT, or internal knowledge for a particular security gap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midday</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/midday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/midday/</guid>
      <description>Phase 2️⃣ Midday ☀️ The “Midday” phase is normally the longest phase from the detection lifecycle, during which the detection has been engineered and commissioned to production. The phase monitors the detection during its operation and aims to improve it if needed. High level goals for the Midday phase: Operate and monitor the detection for FP or TP Improve the detection logic in case of influx of FP Perform systematic reviews to ensure relevancy Functions Goal Description Guidelines Monitor&lt;/&gt; Run as per defined schedule Detection is configured to run on pre-defined schedule or real time if applicable Detections will run based on the schedule set during the sunrise phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/phases/sunset/</guid>
      <description>Phase 3️⃣ Sunset 🌆 During the “Sunset” phase the detection is taken out of commission. The phase wants to ensure that resources are not spent for outdated detections that are no longer applicable and at the same time leave sufficient trace of the existence of the detection. High level goals for the Sunset phase:
Decommission the detection and leave it in a state that it can be resumed anytime Preserve knowledge Functions Goal Description Guidelines Decommission Decommission the detection The goal is to decommission the detection by following process that provides visibility In order to decommission a detection simply change the status field to &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
