<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Framework on ODEF</title>
    <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Framework on ODEF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 21:29:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.odef.wiki/odef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Purpose ODEF enables organization to create and apply principles and best practices for detection engineering. Utilizing it leads to service and process improvements and maturity.
The Framework focuses on using business goals and outcomes to drive and guide cybersecurity activities to deliver detections, improve visibility, minimize vendor dependencies and ultimately improve the organization security posture. The Framework provides the principles that guide efficient and effective detection engineering practices and also provides three maturity levels to measure the organization performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/framework-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.odef.wiki/odef/framework-core/</guid>
      <description>Framework Core The Framework Core provides a set of activities to achieve specific cybersecurity outcomes and references examples of how to achieve those outcomes.
Functions, Goals, Guidelines There are set of functions, goals and guidelines for each phase from the detection lifecycle. Functions, goals, guidelines help the detection engineer to have north star focus and deliver a detection with exceptional quality.
Functions Similarly to python functions those are single goal activities that return or drive particular outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
